Guide to the Steffi Domike Papers, 1946-2009 AIS.1997.20
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Audio/Visual Materials, IX.
  - Assorted Audio, 10.
    - Johnny Hodgson Bluefields, May 1988; 1 Audio Cassette (Box 70, Cassette 27)
    - Skoki, Poland, January 1997; 1 Audio Cassette (Box 70, Cassette 28)
    - Old Bedford Village Orientation Video Soundtrack, 1 Audio Cassette (Box 70, Cassette 29)
    - Interview with Harold Ruttenberg (Kitty R. at end), July 14, 1991; 1 Audio Cassette (Box 70, Cassette 30)
    - Old Bedford Village-House ZNarratives, 1 Audio Cassette (Box 70, Cassette 31)
    - Melva Zetz, March 20, 1987; 1 Audio Cassette (Box 70, Cassette 32)
    - Bill Gaughan-Homestead Works Tour, 1 Audio Cassette (Box 70, Cassette 33)
    - Ruttenberg, 1 Audio Cassette (Box 70, Cassette 34)
    - Merle Haggard, 1 Audio Cassette (Box 70, Cassette 35)
    - Battle of Homestead Tapes #1-3, July 6, 1996; 3 Audio Cassettes (Box 70, Cassette 36-38)
    - River Ran Red Mono Voices, December 28, 1993; 1 Audio Cassette (Box 70, Cassette 39)
    - River Ran Red Long Version Final Stereo, December 28, 1993; 1 Audio Cassette (Box 70, Cassette 40)
    - River Ran Red Stereo Mix Minus Voice, December 28, 1993; 1 Audio Cassette (Box 70, Cassette 41)
    - Women of Steel Bounce Reel, 1 Reel to Reel (Box 71, Reel 42)
    - Women of Steel "Fight Back" Song, 1 Reel to Reel (Box 71, Reel 43)
    - Women of Steel Test Tones, 1 Reel to Reel (Box 71, Reel 44)
    - Old Bedford Village - Video Sound Mixed Track Stereo, 2 Reel to Reels (Box 71, Reel 45-46)
    - Marshall Chapman "Me, I'm Feelin' Free", 1 Reel to Reel (Box 71, Reel 47)
    - WAR Film; Jason in Classroom, 1 Reel to Reel (Box 71, Reel 48)
    - Lisa and Nancy at Busstop, 1 Reel to Reel (Box 71, Reel 49)
    - RRR PHMC Talk - S. Domike, 1 Audio Cassette (Box 71, Cassette 50)
    - River Ran Red Voiceover Uuttakes, 1 Audio Cassette (Box 71, Cassette 51)
    - Women of Steel Video Mix Master (Box 71, Reel 52)
  - Photographs, 11.
    This subseries contains photographs and slides which contributed to Domike's many productions. Included are reproductions of images used in The River Ran Red anthology, as well as original photographs used in Crashin' Out: Hard Times in McKeesport and Women of Steel. Also documented are several labor demonstrations and rallies, as well as the last day of work at the USX Duquesne steel mill.
    Prior to the addition of new materials in October 2011, this subseries existed as Series VIII. The new materials added largely document Domike's involvement in the Mon-Valley Unemployment Committee's Oral History Project and her various artworks, exhibits and installations. Electronic media in the form of CD-ROMS and zip and floppy disks have also been added. Hard copies of the interview with Monsignor Rice and narratives for Terminal Time have been included in the collection.
    - The River Ran Red Anthology Images (Box 11, Folder 1-3)
    - Pittsburgh Scenes, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - West Homestead Historical Sites (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - New York Society Library (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - The River Ran Red Photographs and Negatives (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - The River Ran Red Location Shots, Loch Rannoch, Scotland (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Crashin' Out: Hard Times in McKeesport, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Crashin' Out: Hard Times in McKeesport Slides, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 10-12)
    - Shutdown at Duquesne Slides, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous Slides, 1983-1984 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - New Material Added, 2011
      - Contact sheets and negatives of Labor's Corner, undated (Box 75, Folder 1)
      - Contact sheets and negatives of McKeesport, Early 1980's (Box 75, Folder 2)
      - Contact sheets and negatives of MVUC attendees at the "Lobby in D.C. for Jobs.", 1983 (Box 75, Folder 3)
      - Contact sheets and negatives of the Mon-Valley Unemployed Committee (MVUC) McKeesport Oral History Project (Sleeve #1-16), 1983 (Box 75, Folder 4)
      - Contact sheets and negatives of the MVUC McKeesport Oral History Project (Sleeve #17-44, excluding #29-39), 1983 (Box 75, Folder 5)
      - Contact sheets and negatives of the MVUC McKeesport Oral History Project (Sleeve #45-63), 1983 (Box 75, Folder 6)
      - Contact sheets and negatives of the MVUC McKeesport Oral History Project (Sleeve #64-82), 1983 (Box 75, Folder 7)
      - Contact sheets and negatives of the MVUC March for Survival (Sleeve #29-39), 1983 (Box 75, Folder 8)
      - Contact sheets and negatives of MVUC Rally, 1982 (Box 75, Folder 9)
      - Contact sheets and negatives of production, unknown, undated (Box 75, Folder 10)
      - Contact sheets and negatives of trip to Poland for "Bloodlines" Art Installation and Performance, 1999 (Box 75, Folder 11)
      - Electronic Media, Interview with Monsignor Rice, Floppy Disk, undated (Box 75, Folder 12)
      - Electronic Media, Terminal Time Images, Moving Image and Sound Files, CD ROM, undated (Box 75, Folder 13-14)
      - Electronic Media, Terminal Time Narratives, Floppy Disk, undated (Box 75, Folder 15)
      - Electronic Media, Terminal Time Images, Moving Images and Sound Files, Zip Drive, undated (Box 75, Folder 16)
      - Photographs of the Duquesne Steel Works, 1918 (Box 75, Folder 17)
      - Photographs of the Homestead Pump House, 1990's (Box 75, Folder 18)
      - Photographs of the Mon-Valley Unemployed Committee, undated (Box 75, Folder 19)
      - Slides, Anti KKK Rally and CMU Graduate Student Hallway, 1994-1997 (Box 75, Folder 20)
      - Slides, "Bearing North" exhibition, 1998 (Box 75, Folder 21)
      - Slides, Homestead Shots and Stills of the River Ran Red, undated (Box 75, Folder 22)
      - Slides, Industrial Shots of Duquesne, undated (Box 75, Folder 23)
      - Slides, Industrial Shots of McKeesport and Downtown Pittsburgh, undated (Box 75, Folder 24)
      - Slides, Industrial Shots of Pittsburgh and Surrounding Area, undated (Box 75, Folder 25)
      - Slides, Industrial Shots of Pittsburgh, Duquesne, McKeesport and Workers Being Interviewed, undated (Box 75, Folder 26)
      - Slides, Industrial Shots of Pittsburgh and United Steelworkers Meeting, undated (Box 75, Folder 27)
      - Slides, Industrial Shots of Unidentified Location, undated (Box 75, Folder 28)
      - Slides, Interior of Steel Mill, undated (Box 75, Folder 29)
      - Slides, "Lines of Power" Art Installation at CMU, 1997 (Box 75, Folder 30)
      - Slides, "Mapping the Heap", 1997 (Box 75, Folder 31)
      - Slides, "Mapping the Heap" and trip to Skoki, Poland for presentation of "Bloodline" Art Installation, 1997 (Box 75, Folder 32)
      - Slides, McKeesport and Downtown Pittsburgh, undated (Box 75, Folder 33)
      - Slides, Mill Interior and Industrial Shots of Pittsburgh and Surrounding Area, undated (Box 75, Folder 34)
      - Slides, MVUC and United Steelworkers Meeting, undated (Box 75, Folder 35)
      - Slides, Oakland, Downtown Pittsburgh and Surrounding Areas, undated (Box 75, Folder 36)
      - Slides, Personal Shots and Homestead Pump House, undated (Box 75, Folder 37)
      - Slides, Pittsburgh and Nicaragua, 1989 (Box 75, Folder 38)
      - Slides, subRosa Show, Miller Gallery at Carnegie Mellon, 2000 (Box 75, Folder 39)
      - Slides, United Steelworkers of America Meeting and Visit with Jesse Jackson, undated (Box 75, Folder 40)
      - Slides, United Steelworkers of America Meeting, Workers being Interviewed, and Poland, 1997 (Box 75, Folder 41)
      - Slides, United Steelworkers Meeting and Anti-Reagan Rally, circa 1983 (Box 75, Folder 42)
      - Slides, Squirrel Hill, 1990's (Box 75, Folder 43)
      - Slides, Various Projects, Installations and Exhibits, 1997-2008 (Box 75, Folder 44)
      - Slides, Various Slides of Photographs By: Sue Wribican, 1989-1993 (Box 75, Folder 45)
- Personal Material, 1982-2007; X.
  This new series, added to the collection October 2011, largely consists of materials relating to Domike's personal life, as well as some professional materials that document her work as an educator. Included are correspondence, conference materials, awards, as well as various resumes and CV's. Syllabi from classes she taught at Chatham are also included.
  - Awards Received from Art Institute, 1982-1983 (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - Clippings of Newspaper Photographs Done while at the Daily Herald, 1984 (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - Conferences, 1991-2003 (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence with The Historical Society of Western Pennsylvania Concerning Teaching Resources, 1993 (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence with Nakano Rie Regarding Women of Steel, 1987 (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - Creative Arts Award and Women's Shelter, 1987 (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - Curriculum Vitae and Resume Materials, 1999-2001 (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - Invitation to Present Women of Steel at Carnegie Museum of Art, 1996 (Box 72, Folder 8)
  - Letter Regarding Invitation to Speak at Meeting of University and College Labor Educator's Association, 1989 (Box 72, Folder 9)
  - Notes, undated (Box 72, Folder 10)
  - Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission Research, Presentation and Talk, 1993 (Box 72, Folder 11)
  - Personal Calendar, 1979 (Box 72, Folder 12)
  - Personal Calendar, 2007 (Box 72, Folder 13)
  - Personal Correspondence with Ann Walko, 1992 (Box 72, Folder 14)
  - Personal Correspondence with Kathleen Ferri, 1992-1994 (Box 72, Folder 15)
  - Piece on Domike Published in Pittsburgh, 1988; Original Pittsburgh Magazine as well as paper copy of article included. (Box 72, Folder 16)
  - Pittsburgh History Reference Materials for Class Use, 2000 (Box 72, Folder 17)
  - Presentation, Correspondence and Materials Relating to Workshop Titled, "Life and Labor in the Industrial Valley: A Millennial Perspective", 1999 (Box 72, Folder 18)
  - Press, 1985-2000 (Box 72, Folder 19)
  - Script for Presentation of Various Projects, undated (Box 72, Folder 20)
  - Syllabi for Classes Taught at Chatham, undated (Box 72, Folder 21)
  - Research for Trip to Poland, undated (Box 72, Folder 22)
  - Research for Trip to Russia, 1989-1990 (Box 72, Folder 23)
  - Talk Delivered at SEIU Regional Women's Conference, undated (Box 72, Folder 24)
  - Transcript of Domike Interview for Pittsburgh Oral History Project, undated (Box 72, Folder 25)
- Production Materials, 1986-1999; XI.
  This new series, added to the collection October 2011, consists of materials that document the various productions Domike was involved in, both as a director and/or producer. These include Life Without Father, Nicarribe, On Camera and Working Pittsburgh.
  - Life Without Father, 1987-1988; 1.
    Life Without Father was directed by Domike and released in 1990. The documentary examined the rise of mothers deciding to bear and raise children without fathers, otherwise known as "single-motherhood-by-choice." Throughout planning and production the film went through a number of name changes being known as "Significant Mothers," "Single Mothers," and "Being Mom, Being Single." Materials include grant applications, transcripts of interviews, and production materials.
    - Film Notes, undated (Box 72, Folder 26)
    - Grant Applications, Proposals and Correspondence, 1987 (Box 72, Folder 27)
    - Group Interview, "Concerning Single Motherhood", 1987 (Box 72, Folder 28)
    - Interview of Donna Jo McDaniels, 1988 (Box 72, Folder 29)
    - Interview of Doreen Chimner, 1988 (Box 72, Folder 30)
    - Interview of Fran Bartkowski, 1988 (Box 72, Folder 31)
    - Interview of Rachel Naismith, 1988 (Box 72, Folder 32)
    - Interview of Regina Buckner, 1988 (Box 72, Folder 33)
    - Preliminary Scripts and Notes, 1987 (Box 72, Folder 34)
    - Press Materials, 1991 (Box 72, Folder 35)
    - Scripts and Edits, 1990 (Box 72, Folder 36)
    - Summary and Discussion Guide to Significant Mothers, undated (Box 72, Folder 37)
    - Video Tape Logs, 1987 (Box 72, Folder 38)
  - Nicarribe: Nicaragua's Atlantic Coast, 1988-1999; 2.
    Nicarribe: Nicaragua's Atlantic Coast was directed and co-produced by Domike. It was released in 1988 as a one hour documentary covering the complex internal struggle for cultural and political autonomy of the ethnically diverse people on Nicaragua's Atlantic Coast. Items Include grant materials, correspondence and research materials. The film garnered to awards in 1989. It earned the Silver Star Award at the Sacramento International Film and Video Festival and an Honorable Mention by the Film Council of Greater Columbus Ohio.
    - Application for Funding, 1988-1989 (Box 72, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 72, Folder 40)
    - Research, 1988-1989 (Box 72, Folder 41-42)
  - On Camera, 1989-1996; 3.
    On Camera was a series featured on Pittsburgh public television station WQEX. Produced by Domike, this hour long program featured independently produced film and video from Pennsylvania, West Virginia and Ohio. Materials include entry forms, episode summaries and materials related to production.
    - Budget, 1990 (Box 72, Folder 43)
    - List of Aired Artist's Works, 1989 (Box 72, Folder 44)
    - List of Entries and Entry Forms, 1989 (Box 72, Folder 45)
    - Publicity, undated (Box 72, Folder 46)
    - Release Forms and Relative Paperwork, 1996 (Box 72, Folder 47)
    - Summary of Episodes, 1989 (Box 72, Folder 48)
    - Judges Memo (Box 72, Folder 49)
  - Working Pittsburgh, 1986-1987; 4.
    Working Pittsburgh was a documentary that focused on Pittsburgh laborers documenting everyone from construction workers to the communication sector and service workers.
    - Interview of Anne Parks Cook, 1987 (Box 73, Folder 17)
    - Interview of Clifford Caldwell, 1987 (Box 73, Folder 18)
    - Interview of Frank Lupinacci, 1987 (Box 73, Folder 19)
    - Interview of I.W. Abel, 1986 (Box 73, Folder 20)
    - Interview of Rosemary Trump, 1987 (Box 73, Folder 21)
    - Interview of Sam Papa, 1987 (Box 73, Folder 22)
    - Interview of Shirley Salata, 1987 (Box 73, Folder 23)
    - Interview of Walter Kliss, 1987 (Box 73, Folder 24)
    - Production Notes, 1987 (Box 73, Folder 25)
  - Other Productions, 1986-1999; 5.
    This subseries contains materials relating to Domike's film and video projects and includes production notes, grant materials, video logs, and interviews.
    - Assorted Notes for Labor's Corner, undated (Box 73, Folder 26)
    - Assorted Materials for Women of Steel, 1988 (Box 73, Folder 27)
    - Building Pittsburgh Meeting Agenda, 1989 (Box 73, Folder 28)
    - Building Pittsburgh Script for Recut, undated (Box 73, Folder 29)
    - Description of Out of This Furnace: A Walking Tour of Thomas Bell's Novel, undated (Box 73, Folder 30)
    - Grant Proposal to the NEH for Colossus Transformed, 1988 (Box 73, Folder 31-32)
    - Grant Proposal for Labor's Corner, 1987 (Box 73, Folder 33)
    - Interviews, Tape Logs and Notes for Building Pittsburgh, 1988 (Box 73, Folder 34)
    - John and Sarah, undated (Box 73, Folder 35)
    - Log Sheet for Penn State Video, undated (Box 73, Folder 36)
    - Log Sheet for Win-Win Bargaining, undated (Box 73, Folder 37)
    - Miscellaneous Film Notes, undated (Box 73, Folder 38)
    - Mon Valley Media Business, 1986 (Box 73, Folder 39)
    - Mon Valley Media Notes, 1999 (Box 73, Folder 40)
    - Log of Videos for Labor, undated (Box 73, Folder 41)
    - Penn State Department of Labor Video Project on Worker Health and Safety, 1990 (Box 73, Folder 42)
    - Proposal, Planning and Budget for Broadcast of the Arts, 1988 (Box 73, Folder 43)
    - Questions for Interview with Guatemalan Union Worker, undated (Box 73, Folder 44)
    - Right of Entry Agreement for the Videotaping of Construction Work at Dick Enterprises, 1988 (Box 73, Folder 45)
    - Script and Layout for Old Bedford Village Orientation Video, 1996 (Box 73, Folder 46)
    - Skit for Labor Pains, undated (Box 73, Folder 47)
    - Steel Valley Authority (SVA) Interview Transcripts, Log Sheets and Tape Inventories, undated (Box 73, Folder 48)
    - Synopsis of Various Television Projects Involving MILRITE (Making Industry and Labor Right and Today's Economy), undated (Box 73, Folder 49)
    - Tape Log of IW Abel Interview, 1984 (Box 73, Folder 50)
    - What Do We Win Video Logs, 1996 (Box 73, Folder 51)
    - Who Is The We Legal Releases, 1995 (Box 73, Folder 52)
- Projects, 1983-2006; XII.
  Materials in this subseries relate to exhibits, installations and other projects, such as the Battle of Homestead Foundation in which Domike was involved.
  Additional materials relating to her various exhibits and installations can be found within Audio/Visual Materials.
  - Exhibits and Installations, 1997-2002; 1.
    Materials Included in this subseries to the many exhibits and installations Domike produced, both independently and collaboratively.
    - Bloodline, 1997 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Googling Carnegie, undated (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Mapping the Heap, 1997 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Press Release for Art Institute Gallery Showing, undated (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Representing Carnegie in the Media: From Television to the Web, circa 2000 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - The River's Edge, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Terminal Time, 1998-2002 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Galley Exhibition Announcement Cards, undated (Box 74, Folder 7)
  - Battle of Homestead Foundation, 1996-2004; 2.
    As a chair of the memorial committee for the Battle of Homestead Foundation, Domike was instrumental in the implementation of the memorial pump house and museum at the Battle of Homestead. Included in this subseries are materials that document the planning of the memorial site.
    - Blueprint of Site Landscaping Proposal, undated (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Homestead Reference Materials, 1999-2003 (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - Interpreting the Pump House-Homestead 1892-1990's: Report and Recommendations, which includes a report by Domike titled "Images of the Homestead Pumphouse", 1996 (Box 74, Folder 10)
    - Letter Requesting Proposal for Memorial Sculpture at the Battle of Homestead Site, 2001 (Box 74, Folder 11)
    - Site Planning for Pumphouse and Museum, 1997-2004 (Box 74, Folder 12)
    - Various Materials, 2000-2001 (Box 74, Folder 13)
  - subRosa, 1999-2006; 3.
    subRosa was founded in 1988 as a "reproducible cyberfeminist cell of cultural researchers committed to combining art, activism, and politics to explore and critique the intersections of digital information and bio technologies on women's bodies, lives, and work." Members travelled throughout the world, using performance art, exhibits, and lectures to help spread their message. Domike was an active member of the subRosa art collective.
    - "Biosex and Gender Ed" Show, 2000 (Box 74, Folder 14)
    - Biotech Sex and Gender Workbook, 2000 (Box 74, Folder 15)
    - Biotechnology and Reproduction Research, undated (Box 74, Folder 16)
    - Cultures of Technology, 2006 (Box 74, Folder 17)
    - DVD of Selected Projects, 2000-2005 (Box 74, Folder 18)
    - "The Economies of Art", 2001 (Box 74, Folder 19)
    - Email Correspondence, 1999 (Box 74, Folder 20-21)
    - Gallery Exhibit Announcement Cards, 2000-2002 (Box 74, Folder 22)
    - Glossary for Sex and Gender in the Biotech Century, undated (Box 74, Folder 22)
    - Invitation to "Very Cyberfeminist International" held in Hamburg, 2001 (Box 74, Folder 23)
    - "Knowing Bodies", 2000 (Box 74, Folder 24)
    - Newsletter, undated (Box 74, Folder 25)
    - Notes, undated (Box 74, Folder 26)
    - Pamphlet, undated (Box 74, Folder 27)
    - Proposal for Workshop, 2000 (Box 74, Folder 28)
    - Third Annual Women's Studies Colloquium, 2002 (Box 74, Folder 29)
  - Other Projects, 1983-2001; 4.
    This subseries contains materials relating to projects in which Domike was involved such as the Fannie Sellins Memorial Committee, "Crashin' Out", the Pittsburgh Teachers Institute and the Summer Youth Employment and Training Program.
    - "Crashin' Out" Slide Presentation and Storyboard for Art Institute Class, 1983 (Box 74, Folder 30)
    - Fannie Sellins Memorial Committee, 1989-1990 (Box 74, Folder 31)
    - MVUC Summer Youth Employment Services Funding and Planning, 1983 (Box 74, Folder 32)
    - Pittsburgh Teacher's Institute Teaching Packet for "Interdisciplinary Views of Pittsburgh", 2000 (Box 74, Folder 34)
    - Pittsburgh Teachers Institute Curriculum Unit on Pittsburgh's Environmental History, 2001 (Box 74, Folder 33)
    - Research and Ethnographic Survey of Turtle Creek Valley, 1992 (Box 74, Folder 35)
    - Summer Youth Employment and Training Program (SYETP), 1994 (Box 74, Folder 36)
    - The Patriot Act Game Materials (Box 74, Folder 37)
    - Project Photo Slides (Box 74, Folder 38)
- Research Materials, 1973-2009; XIII.
  This series contains materials relating to research done for various productions and projects. A majority of the materials consist of labor history reference materials.
  - An Outline of Pennsylvania Labor History, 1780-2000 (Box 74, Folder 39)
  - Arbitration Award for Grievance Filed by the USC and United Steelworkers of America, 1981 (Box 74, Folder 40)
  - Arrests and Court Cases in Homestead, 1892 (Box 74, Folder 41)
  - Bibliography and Video Resources of Pittsburgh History Compiled by Domike, 2000 (Box 74, Folder 42)
  - Detroit Auto Uprising 1973 By: Jack Weinberg, 1974 (Box 74, Folder 43)
  - The Great Battle of Homestead Coloring Book, 1993 (Box 74, Folder 44)
  - "Harmony in 1811" from Travels in the United States of America By: John Melish, 2003 (Box 74, Folder 45)
  - History of the Steelworkers Union By: Staughton Lynd, 1973 (Box 74, Folder 46)
  - Labor Filmography Compiled by Fauss, 1983 (Box 74, Folder 47)
  - Have You Heard Her Name?, Unpublished Manuscript on Fannie Sellens By: Miriam Brill Schultz, undated (Box 74, Folder 48)
  - Our Old Brownsville By: Margie McKinley, 1988 (Box 74, Folder 49)
  - Pittsburgh Labor History Resources, 1992 (Box 74, Folder 50)
  - Pennsylvania Labor History Journal, Vols. 19,29,31, 1997-2009 (Box 74, Folder 51)
  - Proclamation for Stagehands Union, 1987 (Box 74, Folder 52)
  - Research on History of Coal in Connelsville Region, 1992 (Box 74, Folder 53)
  - Research and Planning for Film on Alternatives to Military Recruitment, 1986-1988 (Box 74, Folder 54)
  - Topical Materials, This folder includes various newpaper clippings that cover updates in the steel industry and union news, a Pittsburgh Magazine, a Bill from the Pennsylvania House session of 1987, a letter involoving DSL Financial Services, and a soft cover book titled "The People Make History". " (Box 74, Folder 55)
- Oversize Material, 1912-2000; XIV.
  This series contains oversize materials such as photographs, posters, and other art related materials.
  - Battle of Homestead Cartoon by Bill Yund, signed and numbered prints 163 and 166 of 250, 1999; 2 items (Oversize 77, Folder 1)
  - General Plan of Homestead Steel Works, 1912 (Oversize 77, Folder 2)
  - Illustrations Used in The River Ran Red, undated (Oversize 77, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs, 1980's (Oversize 77, Folder 4)
  - Photographs of Students Involved in the McKeesport Oral History Project, 1987 (Oversize 77, Folder 5)
  - Photographs of the Seneca Peace Encampment, undated (Oversize 77, Folder 6)
  - Photographs Taken While Working for the Daily Herald, undated (Oversize 77, Folder 7)
  - Poster for "Mapping the Heap", 1997 (Oversize 77, Folder 8)
  - Student Work, undated (Oversize 77, Folder 9)
  - The Patriot Act Game, 2004 (Oversize 77, Tube 1)
  - America's Industrial Heritage Project and Homestead Centennial Posters, undated (Map-case 16, Drawer 13, Folder 1)
  - Poster for Film Premiere of The River Ran Red, 1993 (Map-case 16, Drawer 13, Folder 2)
  - Pre-Site Plan for Restoration of The Waterworks Homestead Steel by Casey Architects, undated (Map-case 16, Drawer 13, Folder 3)